Michael Hoang Tran

+1 (801) 634-7693 | michaeltranperson@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/michael-tran-20462112a/ | mikesenh.com

SUMMARY

I have been working professionally as a Designer for 2 years and as a Developer for 1 year. I have a deep appreciation for both development and design, recognizing the importance of their synergy. I am driven by a passion for continuous learning, creative endeavors, and making a significant impact in the world while positively enriching people's lives.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Programming: HTML,CSS, JavaScript, Python, PHP
- Database Management: MySQL
- UX: User Research, Information Architecture, User Focused Design
- Frameworks / Libraries: Laravel, Svelte, React,
 SvelteKit, TailwindCSS, Bootstrap, Bulma
- **Designed:** Prototyping and Mockup
- Other: Git, Github, Node.js

SOFT SKILLS

- Effective Time Management, Detail Tracking of Assignments, Organizing Data, Customer Focus Mindset and Going Above and Beyond to Achieve Satisfaction.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science - Web and User Experience

2020 - 2022

Weber State University, Ogden, UT

- Emphasis on Full-Stack Web Development, Certification of Completion User Experience Design
- Graduated with a 4.0 GPA, Summa Cum Laude

Associate of Science - Computer Science & Information System

2017 - 2020

Salt Lake Community College, Salt Lake City, UT

 Certification of Completion in Web Programming & Development, Certification of Completion in Computer Science Fundamentals

WORK EXPERIENCE

Frontend Web Developer / Designer

2022 - 2023

The Grace Company, Salt Lake City, UT

- I primarily focus on redesigning the site as well as adding new functionality to the website such as a management system for the live classroom. Other responsibilities included creating sales and product pages and updating content on the site.
- Skills: Laravel, PHP, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, MySQL, Time Management

Web Designer (Contract)

2021 - 2022

Janadhi & Company, Ogden, UT

- In this role I design websites using Figma, I made prototypes and worked with multiple clients to bring their vision to life. Other responsibilities included helping out field agents with cable wiring and updating already existing website content.
- Skills: Professional Cable Wiring, Wordpress and SEO, Content Management, Figma

Microsoft Support Ambassador

2018 - 2020

Education At Work, Salt Lake City, UT

- As a Microsoft Support Ambassador I mainly troubleshoot problems in the Microsoft Suite of tools, where I would diagnose the problem and fix it for the customer in a timely manner.
- Skills: Customer Service, Technical Problem Solving

Passenger Service Agent

2015 - 2018

Prospect, Salt Lake City, UT

- I'd mainly worked as a coordinator directing other agents to places that needed attention, I have many successful days where everything ran smoothly to the point upper management noticed gave me extra responsibilities.
- Skills: Time Management, Teamwork, Customer Service

Custodial Sweeper 2014 - 2016

Salt Lake School District, Salt Lake City, UT

- Routinely simple job of cleaning, disinfecting and vacuuming. When I finish my work early I would help the other custodial in the area, so we could all leave on time.
- Skills: Teamwork, Time Management

REFERENCES

Christina Delima - UX/Product Designer & Visual Designer

Kihei, Hawaii, United States (808) 268-6520 | info@christinashayne.com

Austin Wilcox - Senior Software Developer

Ogden, Utah, United States
(801) 430-5239 | me@theaustinwilcox.com

Zachery Fauver - Graphic Designer

Salt Lake City, Utah, United States (435) 630-9000 | fauverz@gmail.com